topic: Octave/Matlab
deck: All::CS::Languages::Octave/Matlab
notes:
        -
                uuid: 83a3b8c3-f1e1-463c-8592-213f05f7f5ea
                front: "Set PS1"
                back: "`PS1('>> ');`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: e7be4728-9c48-45af-86df-ad43f4e20922
                front: "Don't write out return value of command"
                back: "Semicolon after command"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 8e77f0ca-c4d5-4327-8435-c02d8517990b
                front: "Comment syntax"
                back: "`a = 100; % comment`"
        -
                uuid: 3d4d37f1-e501-413a-8537-83172720a7a8
                front: "Matrix of 2 rows, 3 columns, full of 1"
                back: "`ones(2, 3)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 772a4b1e-9d9e-4f50-a29b-573f8257cf85
                front: "Matrix of 3 rows, 2 columns, full of 0"
                back: "`zeros(3, 2)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: e641a400-e1ed-434f-b682-9d091e7176e9
                front: "Identity matrix 5x5"
                back: "`eye(5)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 907035d1-ee3c-4896-9586-dd3bbe1dd0d2
                front: "List variables in workspace"
                back: "`who`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 1eea9bfa-091d-4811-bb16-f99d533b2411
                front: "Clear out a variable"
                back: "`clear X`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 61f5dfe0-da23-4d8f-9daa-df7c6684578d
                front: "Matrix literal syntax?"
                back: "`A=[1 2; 5 7; 0 1]`"
        -
                uuid: 69eafa55-5181-49c7-b587-74e7168f5129
                front: "Create 2x2 matrix of uniform-distributed numbers [0;1]"
                back: "`rand(2)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: a08727b9-faef-4fd7-acd7-9d6958f5dcc2
                front: "Matrix multiplication"
                back: "`A = ones(2); B = rand(2); C = A * B`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: a6eda362-8b15-4ef3-bac6-459d0faea342
                front: "Create matrix B with 1's where A's element >= 3"
                back: "`B = (A >= 3)`"
        -
                uuid: e7a2a766-cea1-43ad-869b-14f3ffb48b0e
                front: "Matrix transpose"
                back: "`A'`"
        -
                uuid: 2450d5d8-3b67-431f-bc92-c837ff437c8c
                front: "Get number of rows in matrix"
                back: "`A = [1 2; 30 40; 5 6]; size(A, 1)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 8d42ad60-7dc6-4fc3-b944-a793c1c2d25c
                front: "Get number of columns in matrix"
                back: "`A = [1 2; 30 40; 5 6]; size(A, 2)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 42071c0c-b821-4969-aebf-7cb98d6440bd
                front: "Get (num rows, num columns) in matrix"
                back: "`A = [1 2; 30 40; 5 6]; size(A)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 34da977b-ac99-4c04-af13-7976383fac3b
                front: "Get help for command `eye`"
                back: "`help eye`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 699a420f-62e4-4245-9579-06b6595e8480
                front: "Booleans in Octave"
                back: "1 = true, 0 = false"
        -
                uuid: 206fc4da-ee54-413b-a5ee-ce63aeb46532
                front: "`a ~= b`"
                back: "Non-equality operator (!=)"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 674a37db-eb33-4ab6-8f78-48b9519f3c6c
                front: "Element-wise matrix multiplication"
                back: "`A .* B`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 59f707c3-a4b2-4598-8635-8df21af49a10
                front: "Element-wise matrix element squaring"
                back: "`A .^ 2`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 6dd677d7-0828-4a39-a60f-75cd0f5a9ea0
                front: "Matrix (pseudo)inverse"
                back: "`pinv(A)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 12d7f6ac-a696-4eab-b427-42164d6fb8c1
                front: "Print value of variable"
                back: "`disp(X);`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 65f04f06-5241-4ea1-8f32-1b158aab0fb2
                front: "Scalar equality test"
                back: "x == y"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 134fbe0b-07f9-4b10-a7ea-a8fa74e5e11d
                front: "Logical and, or"
                back: "x && y; x || y;"
        -
                uuid: e91cf6ff-fe29-470e-8862-dc9674f5d915
                front: "Pi"
                back: "`pi`"
        -
                uuid: 0048c9ad-fd74-4cf7-b9f9-cd35760bc99c
                front: "Print out formatted string"
                back: "`disp(sprintf('Hello %.2f', a));`"
        -
                uuid: c51f98ce-e615-4d8e-9ab3-ac9874e41b6c
                front: "Set number of printed digits to a few/a lot"
                back: "`format short` / `format long;`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 34bf6129-ee7f-48c6-aa7e-f6e94cda90f1
                front: "`[1.0 1.2 1.4 ... 2.0]`"
                back: "`1.0:0.2:2.0`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 7929c4fd-4d30-4e3d-aecb-506a5edd2de7
                front: "Row vector"
                back: "[1 2 3]"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 7be077f9-3100-452b-a44a-75165a22fe67
                front: "Column vector"
                back: "[1; 2; 3]"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 2560914b-bab8-4a66-bc77-04a2904c703a
                front: "Number of items in row or column vector"
                back: "length(x)"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 7f5195e3-8a57-4429-a9d7-ec8eeb681fc7
                front: "Select vector items 2, 3, 4, 5. Works both for row and column vectors."
                back: "`x(2:5)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 6dfb9987-01a5-4be1-8eed-baeeab9338a0
                front: "Append column to matrix"
                back: "`A = [A, [100; 101; 102]]`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: d239981f-6f63-4632-97e5-ee346c0d9fc7
                front: "Elementwise reciprocal"
                back: "1 ./ v"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 2930f816-019c-4a3c-8447-698e0714eb10
                front: "Matrix 3x3 full of 3's"
                back: "ones(3) + 2"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 73835cf2-539b-4723-abbb-5ee6f2f33941
                front: "Get list of indices where vector `x` is greater than 5"
                back: "`x = [1 10 2 20]; find(x > 5)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 93f86d82-1d59-434e-9552-e1b8a7f5be77
                front: "Return list of non-zero indices in vector"
                back: "`find`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 4d90cb9a-5d0c-4650-93aa-f5301e0816c6
                front: "Return 5x5 magic square"
                back: "`magic(5)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: f76eb94c-d26f-4950-ae17-68b62b5acde2
                front: "Multiply together entire vector"
                back: "`prod(v)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: c87c0a29-f952-4cc8-a605-8ee26162f88a
                front: "Vectorize matrix by appending rows together"
                back: "`A(:)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 05a011c3-9105-42c4-87dc-42eb6641f9f2
                front: "Get matrix second column"
                back: "`A(:,2)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: e1836723-454b-46b5-8d7c-8a43185714d7
                front: "Get matrix second row"
                back: "`A(2,:)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 8ad384c5-db2a-4501-85af-e790e019d982
                front: "Get floor of value"
                back: "`B = floor(A)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 642a992b-6b30-40d2-9b87-2a3ddf39ccfc
                front: "Get ceiling of value"
                back: "`ceil(a)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 885b43dc-73f8-44fc-8bcf-56057c8b86bf
                front: "Save value in `v` into `.mat` (Octave/Matlab) format"
                back: "`save hello.mat v`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 3d388c79-db2c-42b3-96df-1b9d8e946e67
                front: "Clear out entire environment"
                back: "`clear`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 25d2578f-286e-4e6d-b1dc-276d59c2ac96
                front: "Show the histogram of `x`"
                back: "`hist(x)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 4b0d81e0-6d5b-4987-8ae6-a6921e74ebc6
                front: "Get random matrix (5 rows, 3 columns), Gaussian-distributed, mean = 0, variance = 1"
                back: "`randn(5,3)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 2d33f359-b866-4ef2-b80f-60bfe67821a7
                front: Save string into variable
                back: "`b = 'hi';`"
        -
                uuid: a66260c1-871e-43b2-b597-fbcbbbd8bb2a
                front: Get working directory
                back: "`pwd`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 8f7bb9ea-7dd1-4dd9-8b44-5fdb7058d8d9
                front: Flip matrix up-down
                back: "`flipud(X)`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 998dc10f-bbf0-4364-983f-3ec838e826d4
                front: Variable storing last result
                back: "`ans`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: cba5029c-6619-43fd-a3fa-79af82e3b338
                front: "Get row of matrix column averages"
                back: "`mean(X);`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 9bc495e5-75fc-4b2a-a9f1-1d9562777dbd
                front: "Get column of matrix row averages"
                back: "`mean(X')';`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: b6102852-76e0-4dd2-aee4-bda6541dd1e1
                front: "Get average of vector"
                back: "`avg(a);`"
                include_reverse: true
        -
                uuid: 2990320e-6345-4ea2-ac79-112959beadca
                front: "For-cycle syntax"
                markdown: false
                back: >
                        <code>
                        for i = 1:10<br>
                          disp("Ahoj!");<br>
                        endfor
                        </code>
